Guide to the Collection of Ephemera on the Book in California
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Report of the Trustees of the State Library, 1879-1880 (Box 14)
- Envelope from I. N. Choynski, undated (Box 14)
- The California Florist, Vol. I, No. 6, 1888 October (Box 14)
- Price List of Andrews' Patent Pencil-Holding Noiseless Slates; A. L. Bancroft & Co., undated (Box 14)
- Society of California Pioneers. Memorial of the Life and Services of Washington Bartlett, 1888 (Box 14)
- Photograph of Frederick M. Stocking by J. H. Peters, undated (Box 14)
- Reports of the Committees on California State Library, 1889 (Box 14)
- Bill from A. W. Ericson, Books, Music, Stationery, 1885 (Box 14)
- The Helix Farms Lemons, broadside, undated (Box 14)
- The San Franciscan, Vol. I, No. 6, 1884 March 22 (Box 14)
- Photograph by Runnels & Stateler, undated (Box 14)
- Blank shares for the Argonaut Publishing Company, 1887 June (Box 14)
- Portrait of Adolf Sutro, undated (Box 14)
- Blank check from the Bank of California, account of Bodie Railway and Lumber Co.; printed by G. T. Brown and Co., undated (Box 14)
- Catálogo de las obras publicadas en espanol by the History Company, 1890 (Box 14)
- Material by or relating to Hubert Howe Bancroft, the Bancroft Company, and the Bancroft Library, 1862-1905, undated; 24 (Box 15)
- Material by or relating to Hubert Howe Bancroft, the Bancroft Company, and the Bancroft Library (continued), 1889-1914, undated; 17 (Box 16)
- St. Dunstan's Library, undated (Box 16)
- "Triennial Programme: The Grand Commandery of California", 1880 August (Box 16)
- Material by or relating to Clyde Browne, 1918-1948, undated; 10 (Box 16)
- Advertisement for Voyage to California 1949 by James Ladd Delkin, undated (Box 17)
- The Colt Springs High for 1940, booklist (Box 17)
- California State Library. Do You Know?, 1949 (Box 17)
- Goodspeed, Edgar J. The Aitken Bible; Dawson's Book Shop, 1949 (Box 17)
- Poets of the Pacific, information pamphlet announcing group dedicated to promoting Western poetry, 1941 (Box 17)
- On Account of a Visit to California, 1826-'27; printed at the Grabhorn Press for the Book Club of California, 1941 (Box 17)
- Horace Gunthrop and Son catalogue, circa 1943 (Box 17)
- United States Government Printing Office. Style Manual, 1945 January (Box 17)
- George Barrie and Sons catalogues, 1923-1940, undated (Box 17)
- Bryant, Dolores Waldorf. Charle P. Kimball, San Francisco's "Noisy Carrier", 1940 (Box 17)
- Book Mark catalogue, 1945 (Box 17)
- Dawson's Book Shop catalogue, 1944 Spring (Box 17)
- Crocker, Templeton. Books and Manuscripts, undated; 2 (Box 17)
- Catalog of the Library of Mrs. Francis Carolan, undated (Box 18)
- The Miner's Progress; Or, Scences in the Life of a California Miner; Christmas facsimile souvenir from Carl Hoffman; printed at the Grabhorn Press, 1943 (Box 18)
- Typography, Books, & Printing by Grant Dahlstrom; exhibition catalogue printed at the Castle Press, 1946 (Box 18)
- Colt Press catalogues, 1941-1942; 2 (Box 18)
- Timothy Bookworm; Greenwood Press, 1949 (Box 18)
- Anderson, Keith. My Brother Gregg; printed by Grant Dahlstrom, 1947 (Box 18)
- "Some Notes for a [Quic]keepsake"; The Typophile P.A.B., 1947 October (Box 18)
- California County Free Library. Facts, 1949 (Box 18)
- Announcement of a Roxburghe Club meeting, 1949 November (Box 18)
- Horace Gunthrop catalogue, 1941 November (Box 18)
- "Frederic W. Goudy", 1947 (Box 18)
- Western Books, exhibition catalogues, 1946-1948 (Box 18)
- Grabhorn, Edwin. Some Remarks on the Printed Book; The Quercus Press, 1948 (Box 18)
- San Francisco Art Gallery auction catalogue, 1940 (Box 18)
- Christmas Party Quarterly, H.E. Huntington Library, 1937-1949 (Box 18)
- Ode of Mrs. E. M. Wills; The Press of Muir Dawson, 1947 (Box 18)
- Advertisement of Books of the California Gold Rush by Carl I. Wheat; The Colt Press, circa 1949 (Box 18)
- Five Hundred Years of the Printed Book, 1440-1940; University of California Press (Box 18)
- Bancroft, Philip. Hubert Howe Bancroft, 1948 September 5 (Box 18)
- Material by or relating to Ernest Dawson, 1947, undated; 2 (Box 18)
- Addison, Joseph. "An Essay on Scholarship"; printed by hand at the Hart Press, 1941 (Box 18)
- The "Tribune" Holiday Cook Book, 1884 (Box 19)
- Transactions and Proceedings of the Geographical Society of the Pacific, 1881, 1882 (Box 19)
- Catalogue of the Loan Book Exhibition, Held at the University of California, Berkeley, 1884 (Box 19)
- Samples from O. E. Olsen Lithograph Co., undated (Box 19)
- Mercantile Library Association publications, 1870-1877, undated; 4 (Box 19)
- Biennial Report of the Regents of the University of California for the Years 1872-1873 (Box 19)
- School Law of California, and Rules and Regulations of the State Boards of Education and Examination, 1876 (Box 19)
- Unsorted checks and orders from California bookstores, 1870s (Box 19)
- Letter to H. H. Moore from George Lette, 1873 December 3 (Box 19)
- By-Laws, Rules and Regulations of the Odd Fellows' Library Association, 1870 (Box 19)
- Constitution, By-Laws, List of Members, Catalogue of Library, Rules of the School of Design of the San Francisco Art Association, 1878 (Box 19)
- Annual Announcement of the Medical College of the Pacific, 1875 (Box 19)
- The Pacific Coast Pulpit, Vol. I, No. 1, 1874 (Box 19)
- The California Teacher, Vol. IX, No. 1, 1871 July (Box 19)
- Sunshine, Vol. I, No. 7, 1875 June (Box 20)
- Mechanics' Institute. Concerts at the Mechanics' Pavilion, 1877 March 31 (Box 20)
- Copy of deed between James Lick, the California Academy of Sciences and the Society of California Pioneers, 1874 August (Box 20)
- Willow Dale Press, Vol. I, No. 12, 1879 December (Box 20)
- The Weekly Index, Vol. I, No. 5, 1879 August 28 (Box 20)
- Advertisements for the Argonaut and the Weekly Bulletin Placard, San Francisco newspapers, undated (Box 20)
- Note from I. N. Choynski to Adolph Sutro, 1877 May 9 (Box 20)
- Thompson & West's Prospectus of an Illustrated History of Sutter County, undated (Box 20)
- Letter from J. Rowell to Mrs. E. J. Henry, 1876 June 2 (Box 20)
- Red Hot, Vol. I, No. 1, 1873 May (Box 20)
- San Jose Daily Mercury, 1876 June 7 (Box 20)
- Advertisements for California newspapers, undated; 4 (Box 20)
- R. D. W. Davis and Co. auction catalogue, 1877 (Box 20)
- M. J. O'Connor, Plaintiff, Against B. F. Good et al., Defendants, undated (Box 20)
- Advertisement for J. D. Mason's School for Pennmanship, undated (Box 20)
- Letter from Charles de Young and Co., undated (Box 20)
- Illustrated Postscript of the San Francisco News-Letter, 1870 November 5 (Box 20)
- The Pacific Expositor, 1861; 2 (Box 20)
- Speech of the Honorable Thomas A. Brown, of Contra Costa, on the Bills Prescribing Rules for the Government of the State Library, 1866 (Box 20)
- "A. Roman & Co's Monthly List of New Publications", 1868 November (Box 20)
- The San Francisco Fairy, 1868 (Box 20)
- J. Bithell, Importer of Books and Stationery order form, 1868 June 25 (Box 20)
- Philip Cowen, Petaluma bookstore form, 1863 (Box 20)
- Barra, E. I. Something About Coins, 1863 (Box 20)
- Antiquarian Silver Mining Co., deed and assessment, 1862 (Box 20)
- Mining and Scientific Press, order form, undated (Box 20)
- Steroscopic view of the Mercantile Library, undated (Box 20)
- Sales receipts and checks, 1860-1868; 5 (Box 20)
- Puck, Vol. I, No. 1, 1865 January (Box 20)
- The Masonic Mirror, 1869 (Box 20)
- "New Sabbath School Library Books"; published by Carter & Brothers, 1867 (Box 20)
- The Golden Monthly, Vol. I, No. 1, 1861 January (Box 20)
- The Pacific Law Magazine, Vol. I, No. 1, 1867 January (Box 20)
- Annual reports of the Odd Fellows' Library Association, 1865-1869 (Box 21)
- Hubert Burgess' System of Penmanship in Ten Books, 1865 (Box 21)
- The Overland Monthly, Vol. 2, No. 6, 1869 June (Box 21)
- Stationery with drawing of the New York bookstore in the Russ House, undated (Box 21)
- Society of California Pioneers. Ceremonies at the Laying of the Corner Stone of the New Pioneer Hall, 1862 (Box 21)
- Letter and merchandise receipt from Charles Kimball, 1857, undated (Box 21)
- Letter to the editors of the Mercantile Library Bulletin, undated (Box 21)
- Conveyance of title on sealed paper, in Spanish, signed by "Castro" and Angel Ramirez, 1834 (Box 21)
- Advertisements and drawings of Pioneer Bookstore; Marvin and Hitchcock, Printers, undated (Box 21)
- Draft of a bill providing for the distribution of books by the state of California, 1860 (Box 21)
- Cards, advertisements, and receipts from San Francisco booksellers and stationers, undated (Box 21)
- State of California, issued check, 1852 (Box 21)
- Deeds and early California printing samples, 1849-1853, undated (Box 21)
- Town Talk, 1855 (Box 21)
- Minority Report of the Assembly Committee on State Library on Senate Bill No. 42 and Assembly Bill No. 261, undated (Box 21)
- Daily Evening Journal, 1852; 2 (Box 21)
- The California Pictorial, circa 1858 (Box 21)
- Annual Report of the Secretary of State for the Year 1860 (Box 21)
- The Pacific Expositor, Vol. I, No. 5, 1859 (Box 21)
- The California Culturalist, 1859 May (Box 21)
- Report of the Mercantile Library Association, 1859 (Box 21)
- Letter from John G. Lewis to William H. Davis, 1850 March 6 (Box 21)
  Includes earliest authenticated bookmark in California
- Crawford, Theron Clark. James G. Blaine, 1893 (Box 22)
- Antiquarian Bookman, 1951 July 21 (Box 22)
- The Shirley Letters from California Mines, in 1851-52, 1922; 2 (Box 22)
- Annals of the English Stage; W. J. Widdleton, Publisher, 1865 (Box 23)
- Early stamps of California and Pacific Coast dealers, undated; 2 (Box 23)
- Early stamps of California and Pacific Coast dealers (continued), undated; 2 (Box 24)
- Newbegin's Bookshop compliment slip, undated (Box 24)
- The San Francisco Daily Herald, Vol. I, No. 298, 1851 May 17 (Box 24)
- Annual reports of the Mercantile Library Association, 1871-1893 (Box 24)
- Mechanics' Institute Library, letter and catalogue, 1867, undated (Box 24)
- Unsorted checks, subscription and order forms, correspondence, and other material pertaining to bookselling in California, 1830s-1860s; 6 (Box 25)
- Printing block, undated (Box 25)
- Book Club of California, minutes of two meetings, 1913 (Box 26 (Oversize))
- "George Watson Cole, L. H. D.", undated (Box 26 (Oversize))
- Davis, Robert H. "I Am the Printing Press", 1941 (Box 26 (Oversize))
- Alta California Bookstore administrative files and printing samples, 1922-1936, undated (Box 26 (Oversize))
- John Henry Nash printed material, undated; 3 (Box 26 (Oversize))
- "Printing Is the Interpretation of the Written Melodies of Word"; Knight-Connihan Co., Printers, 1928 (Box 26 (Oversize))
- The Wednesday Press, 1903 February (Box 26 (Oversize))
- "The Sunday World, Los Angeles, Christmas 1893" (Box 26 (Oversize))
- "By-Laws and Regulations of Bernal Lodge Library", 1889 (Box 26 (Oversize))
- The Welcome Visitor, 1880 July (Box 26 (Oversize))
- The Wasp, 1885 April 18 (Box 26 (Oversize))
- Harper's Weekly, 1887 December 31 (Box 26 (Oversize))
- Anti-Kearney poster published by I. N. Choyinski, undated (Box 26 (Oversize))
- Checks and other financial material relating to Joseph Ellery, 1857-1865 (Box 26 (Oversize))
- "Administrator's Sale," broadside announcing booksale at San Jose's Mayor's Office, 1852 November 4 (Box 26 (Oversize))
- "The Celebration in San Francisco", 1858 September 27 (Box 26 (Oversize))
- Daily Evening Picayune, 1852 (Box 26 (Oversize))